It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
어지러운 전국 시대.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
Musashi is here-dasu!
무사시 등장이오!
Karakuri Kengouden
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
A man always dreams of the day
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
in the center of the world to become
제일 강해질 날을
AH! AH! the strongest
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
모험의 길의 막을 연다
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
Go! Fight!
가라! 싸워라!
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
Tomorrow will be glorious
내일은 빛난다
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Fight the utmost with the stillness
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
His eyes shined! Musashi!
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
Because he was late for the registration, Musashi was expelled from the competition.
참가 등록에 늦어 지팡구 무예 대회에서 쫓겨난 무사시.
As Zenigatan helped, he infiltrated into the a competition place and showed his skills.
제니가탄의 도움으로 대회장 하나에 잠입해서 대활약.
But his true identity was revealed, and he had to run away and hide under a floor as he was chased by officials.
그러나 정체가 밝혀져 관리들에게 쫓겨 사찰의 마루 밑에 도망쳐야 했다.
Rescue Senhime
센히메를 구하고 승부이오
In the martial arts competition, preliminary contests were going on in seven places.
이 무예 대회는 7개의 대회장에서 먼저 예선이 진행되고 있었다.
Tenguryū, Bouga no Ken.
천구류, 망아의 검.
The final contestant from the first ground is Ushiwaka!
제 1 대회장 대표 우시와카 님으로 결정!
Shinsengiri!
신선치기!
The final contestant from the second ground is Kondō!
제 2 대회장 대표 콘도 님으로 결정!
Ganryū! Tsubamegaeshi!
간류! 츠바메가에시!
The final contestant from the third ground is Kojirō!
제 3 대회장 대표 코지로 님으로 결정!
Daichōtō Gojō!
대장도 고조!
The final contestant from the fourth ground is Benkei!
제 4 대회장 대표 벤케이 님으로 결정!
Secret Sword! Ichi no Tachi!
비검! 제일의 검!
The final contestant from the fifth ground is Jūbee!
제 5 대회장 대표, 주베 님으로 결정!
Kusarigamaryū! Kubikarigama!
쿠사리가마류! 목 베는 낫!
The final contestant from the sixth ground is Baiken!
제 6 대회장 대표, 바이켄 님으로 결정!
Hōzōinryū! Jigoku Kakakuru Ban!
호조인류! 지옥조종반!
The final contestant from the seventh ground is Hōzōin!
제 7 대회장 대표, 호조인 님으로 결정!
Make way! Make way!
아따! 길을 내쇼! 길을 내시오!
Just as expected; only the best people have been winning all the way.
역시 모두 쟁쟁한 사람들만 이겨 왔구만.
Musashi's name should be here...
마땅히 여기에 무사시 씨의 이름이 있겠지?
Excuse me. Do you know Musashi?
어, 저, 무사시를 알고 계십니까?
Ah, I've given him some trouble before.
아, 조금 폐를 끼쳐서요.
Could you be Otsuru and the monk Takuan?
설마 오츠루 씨에 타쿠안 스님이신지?
That's right.
맞소.
I am Zenigatan.
나는 제니가탄이라고 합니다.
I see. As Musashi always praised, you sure are pretty, Otsuru.
그렇군요. 무사시 씨가 계속 자랑하던 오츠루 씨는 예쁘군.
Also, as I heard, you do look stubborn, monk.
스님도 들은 대로 꽤나 완고해 보이는군요.
-What? -Nah, it's in my words, not his.
-뭐라? -아니, 다르게 말해서.
More importantly, where's Musashi?
그보다 무사시 씨는 어디에 있나요?
That's what I wanted to ask.
그게, 내가 묻고 싶은 거야.
If the one with a truncheon also has no idea...
관리가 그런 걸 모르면 거...
Really, where did he disappear to?
이것 참, 어디에 사라졌는지.
This tastes good-dasu! Good job!
이거 맛있소. 맛있소. 참 잘 했소!
But it's not me who asked you to take these-dasu. These are nothing more than you took by your own free will-dasu.
다만, 내가 가져오라고 말한 거 아니오. 어디까지나 네가 자신의 의지로 가져온 것이오.
Next, I'd like something to drink-dasu...
다음엔 뭔가 마실 거 같은거 원할까나...
Really... even the dogs nowadays don't listen to what I say-dasu.
거참... 요즘 개는 정말 말하는 걸 안 들어서 말이오!
The air isn't good here-dasu.
숨이 막히오.
Outside is the best as always-dasu! How refreshing-dasu!
역시 바깥이 제일이오! 상쾌하오!
blah blah, this is Musashi from Miyamoto village. We'll reward you 10 ryos if you take him directly.
어쩌고저쩌고 미야모토 마을의 무사시, 이 반역자를 잡아오는 자에게는 10량,
We'll reward you 1 ryo if you find out where he is.
거처를 알아낸 자에게는 1량의 상금을,
Then 11 ryos in total!
그럼 총 11량!
-That much? -Let's go get him right away!
-그렇게 많이? -빨리 찾으러 가자!
This, really I can't do something about-dasu...
이건 정말 어렵소...
-Get a grip, Otsuru. -Right.
-힘내라, 오츠루. -네.
Why am I even a traitor-dasu?!
왜 내가 반역자가 되어야만 하오!
I was late for the registration only by a day-dasu!
겨우 하루 접수가 늦었을 뿐인데.
Those blockhead officials!
저 영문을 알 수 없는 관리 놈들!
But still I'm hungry-dasu... Huh?
그래도 배가 고프오... 어라?
Heh, even though the heaven has abandoned me, the river is sending me a love call!
하늘은 날 버려도 빨리 오라고 오라고 강이 사랑하나 보오.
Hey, the love came-dasu! It came-dasu!
오, 사랑이 왔소, 왔소!
I'll take it as my meal!
밥으로 먹을 거라면 이 녀석을!
Wow, an eel skewer-dasu!
우와! 뱀장어꼬치이오!
Wouldn't it be difficult to run away?
달아나기 어렵지 않겠어?
We'll take a good care of you.
귀여워해 줄게.
What a pretty clothes you're putting on.
예쁜 걸 입고 그래.
Is she trying to look angry?
화난 척 하는 것일까나?
Even if you whirl such thing, you'll end up being injured!
그런 걸 휘둘러도 상처를 입을 뿐이지!
Gimme that!
일로 넘겨라!
How stupid!
이 새끼가!
That would make some money!
이건 돈이 되겠어!
Who's that?!
누구냐!
I'm a passerby-dasu.
지나가던 자이오.
Why did you step on my hand?!
왜 손을 밟냐!
I was just walking by, and you stick out your hand on your own-dasu.
사람이 걸어가고 있는데 그쪽이 멋대로 손을 내밀었소.
What?!
뭐시라?
-Hey, he's Musashi! -What?
-어, 이놈 무사시다! -뭐라!?
Th- that's true! He definitely looks like Musashi!
저, 정말이다, 무사시다. 수배자의 인상하고 꼭이야!
If we get him, they'll award us 10 ryos!
잡으면 10량이야!
We'll take that!
우리가 가져가겠다!
Awesome, awesome! Aren't you strong, Musashi!?
대단해, 대단해! 무사시는 강하구나!
These bunch are nothing!
뭘 그러오. 이런 패거리!
Thank you.
고마워.
Is something on my head-dasu?
뭔가 묻었소?
No, that's not it. I thought a traitor appeared in the competition would be a scary person...
아니, 그게 아니라 무예 대회에 나타난 반역자라니까 더 무서운 사람일 거라 생각했는데...
but aren't you a cool young person! Totally unexpected!
의외로 멋진 젊은이잖아!
C- cool?
머, 멋지오?
Huh?
어라?
I never had something this tasty-dasu.
이런 맛있는 것은 태어나서 처음 먹소.
If you need more, I'll order more for you.
부족하면 더 주문할게.
But still, I never saw someone collapsing because of extreme hunger!
그래도 배가 너무 고파서 쓰러지는 건 난 태어나서 처음 봐!
How unsightly shape I showed to you-dasu!
꼴불견인 모습을 보이고 말았소.
But, why are you offering me food instead of letting the officials know-dasu?
근데 날 관리에게 날리지 않고 왜 밥을 먹여주시오?
Listening to your story, it makes perfect sense that you went wild, Musashi!
사정을 알고 보면 무사시가 날뛴 것에도 무리가 없어!
I would get angry too!
나도 화나겠다!
Thank you for understanding-dasu.
알아 주셨다면 감사하오.
Hey, hey!
있잖아, 있잖아!
More importantly, Musashi, let's go on a journey!
그보다 무사시, 여행하러 가자!
Right, with me!
응, 나하고 같이!
With you?
당신하고?
I wanted to go on a journey, so I ran out from my house!
나, 정말로 여행가고 싶어서 집을 뛰쳐나왔어.
You've run away from home?
그러니까 가출?
And then, weird guys were gathering onto me!
그랬더니 이상한 놈들에게 노려지고!
If you ran away from your home, does that mean you don't have enough money...?
가출했다면 돈이 별로 없다는 말...?
-Right! -As expected...
-응! -역시...
What's wrong, Musashi?
왜 그래, 무사시?
But... if you don't have money, we'll have to run away...
그래도... 돈이 없으면 먹고 달아날 수밖에...
It's alright even without money! More importantly, let's go on a journey!
돈 따위 없어도 괜찮아. 그보다 같이 여행으로 가자!
No, you will go. This is my order.
아니, 가는 거야. 이건 내 명령이에요.
Order? But I'm...
명령? 그래도 나는...
Are you saying that you still have lingering for the martial arts competition?!
아직 무예 대회에 미련이 있다는 말이에요?
Uh, that is... I have...
아, 그게, 그러니까, 그런 곳에...
Then I have a good idea.
그럼 내게 좋은 생각이 있어.
Go to this place for the payment.
계산은 여기에 받으러 가 줘.
I wonder if it'll be alright-dasu...
괜찮을까...
Certainly!
아, 잘 알겠습니다.
Thank you for waiting!
기다렸지!
-Didn't she get angry-dasu? -Not at all!
-화내지 않았소? -전혀!
Anyway, Musashi, it's a promise that when I manage to get you into the main competition place, we'll go for a journey!
그보다 무사시, 본대회장에 들어가게 해 주면 여행가는 걸로 약속한 거야!
Right-dasu.
그렇소.
You will keep that promise!
꼭 약속이야!
A man does not take his words back-dasu!
사내는 두말하지 않소!
Yay! It's so great!
야호! 최고!
I am a man-dasu.
나, 사내이오.
When seven separate preliminary contest places combine,
7개의 지역 예선장을 합체시키면 결승전을 하는 본대회장이 된다.
Straight lines please!
나란히, 나란히!
Yes, alright! Good!
네, 네! 네!
It's for the body check!
신체 체크이오!
How can we go through such strict guards?
이렇게 엄중한데 어떻게 들어가오?
That's why I told you I have a good idea!
그러니까 좋은 수가 있댔지!
Wh- wha- what're you doing-dasu?!
무, 무슨, 무슨 짓이오!
Don't be misled. I'm not taking all my clothes off.
서두르지 마. 벗는 건 여기까지.
Now, cover yourself well with that.
자, 그걸 잘 뒤집어써.
No matter what, you must not show your face.
어떤 일이 있어도 얼굴을 보이면 안 돼.
I'll make you a gentle esteemed daughter.
곱게 자란 영애로 만들어 줄 거야.
What is a gentle esteemed daughter-dasu?
뭣이오, 곱게 자란 영애라니...
Anyway act like a graceful lady!
어쨌든 정숙한 여성처럼!
Show your ticket.
입장권을 보이시오.
Who is this person here?
근데 이 분은...?
She's a daughter of a noble, soon to leave Miyako Palace.
미야코 궁전을 떠나는 영애로 꼭 무예 대회를 보고 싶다고 해서 데려왔다.
That's impolite! Tell me your name, name, name, name, name, name!
무례하다! 네 이름을 대, 대, 대, 대, 대, 대!
Yes, understood! We're very sorry!
예, 예! 면목없습니다!
-Then, we shall go ahead. -Right! Go ahead!
-그럼 지나간다. -예! 지나가십시오!
Let's go, Princess Musato.
가자, 무사토 공주.
Excuse me-dasu.
실례하오.
Who is this girl? Wait for the stormy latter half!
대체 이 아가씨는 누구인가? 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
We're in the main competition site, as promised.
약속대로 본 대회장에 들어왔어.
Thank you-dasu.
고맙소.
Now it's your turn to keep the promise.
이번엔 네가 약속한 걸 지킬 차례야.
I know-dasu. Wow, that's awesome! Jūbee, Kondō, and everyone are so skilled!
알고 있소. 우와, 대단하오! 주베 씨도 콘도도 대부분 막상막하이오!
Musashi!
무사시!
Ouch... -dasu.
아야야야야, 이오.
Who's this?
뭐야, 얘?
Wh- who's this?!
누, 누구냐!
Musashi.
무사시 님.
Ah, Jūbee!
아, 주베 씨!
Hey, everyone!
우와, 모두!
He is Musashi from Miyamoto village, the one making a mess in the competition, wanted as a traitor.
저 자가 대회를 어지럽히는 반역자로 수배중인 미야모토 마을의 무사시입니다.
Wh- what?!
뭐, 뭐라?
Musashi! No matter what happened, being a traitor is unforgivable! Prepare yourself!
무사시! 어떤 일이 있었던간에 반역자는 절대 용서할 수 없다! 각오해라!
N- no! Wait! Please wait-dasu!
아, 아니오! 잠, 잠깐 기다리시오!
No need for excuse!
변명은 필요없다!
Musashi!
무사시!
You're making me do this-dasu!
어쩔 수 없소!
You're pretty good, Musashi.
꽤나 하는군, 무사시.
Musashi. That was splendid.
무사시 님. 훌륭하오.
It's been a while, Jūbee-dasu!
주베 씨, 오랜만이오!
Musashi. Why are you doing this?
무사시 님. 왜 이런 짓을 하십니까?
Why didn't you participate in the competition in a honest way?
왜 정직하게 무예 대회에 출전하지 않으셨습니까?
I'm sorry-dasu.
미안하오...
I was a little bit late for the registration-dasu...
나, 신청을 아슬아슬하게 못 해서...
Is that so?
저런.
That's totally you, Musashi.
무사시 님 스럽군요.
I'm embarrassed-dasu!
이야! 부끄럽소.
What are you doing, to clap for a traitor?!
반역자에게 박수를 하다니 무슨 짓이냐!
Get him! Get that Musashi guy!
잡아라! 무사시인가 하는 놈, 잡아라!
Whoever defies me is unforgivable, even if it's a child!
짐을 거스르는 자라면 설마 어린이라 해도 용서할 수 없다!
Please wait, shōgun!
기다려 주십시오, 쇼군!
What?
뭐라?
He must be the shōgun Ieyasu...
저 자가 쇼군 이에야스...
What is it, Jūbee?
뭔가, 주베.
This Musashi.
이 무사시,
He did not disturbed the competition with a bad intention.
악의가 있어서 대회에서 난리를 피운 것이 아닙니다.
He was simply a little bit late for the registration.
단지 간발의 차로 마감을 못 맞추었기 때문에...
Whatever the reason is, he did make a trouble.
이유야 어떻든 폐를 끼친 것은 분명하다.
Unforgivable!
용서할 수 없다!
Then please let him have an extra match against me, Jūbee!
그럼 이 주베와 번외 시합을 하게 해 주십시오!
What?
뭐라?
By doing so...
그렇게 하면...
Musashi should be satisfied.
무사시도 만족할 것입니다.
Wow, I'll be satisfied, definitely satisfied! I'll be satisfied if I can have a match with Jūbee-dasu!
우와, 만족하오! 만족하오! 주베 씨하고 하면 만족이오!
Shōgun, I also ask you for that.
쇼군. 저도 부탁드립니다.
Same for me, Shōgun!
마찬가지입니다, 쇼군!
-I ask for your favor! -I also ask you to do so.
-저도 부탁드리오! -저도 부탁드립니다.
Me too!
나도다!
Inevitable. Then I'll ask for that too!
어쩔 수 없지. 그럼 저도 부탁드립니다!
Everyone...
모두...
Shōgun!
쇼군!
Interesting. Will it be a match worth seeing?
음, 흥미롭군. 볼 가치 있는 승부가 될 것인가?
I guarantee that.
보장해드립니다.
Alright. I will allow this as an exception.
좋다. 특별히 허가하지.
Yay!
아싸!
I am very happy to hear that.
분에 넘치는 기쁨입니다.
An extra match will begin now.
지금부터 번외 시합.
Jūbee vs Musashi. One-game match!
주베 님 대 무사시 님, 단판 승부!
Start!
시작!
Excellent job, Jūbee.
대단하군, 주베.
This definitely is interesting.
이건 확실히 흥미롭구나.
Thanks for guiding us to various places.
저런, 이곳저곳 안내도 받고.
That was a great Edotopia sightseeing.
덕분에 에도토피아 구경을 할 수 있었소이다.
It's nothing. We were finding Musashi anyway.
별 말씀을. 무사시 씨를 찾는 김이니까.
So I heard that the final match starts today...
오늘부터 결승전이 시작한다 했으니...
The main competition place is formed by combining each preliminary places.
각 예선 대회장이 하나가 된 본 대회장이지요.
But... it's a martial arts competition without Musashi...
그래도... 무사시 씨가 나오지 않은 무예 대회 따위...
That's right.
그래.
It'll be boring.
봐도 시시하구나.
It somewhat lost its flavor, as I have a guard job.
이쪽도 사실은 경비의 일이 있으니 왠지 맥이 빠지는군요.
I wonder where did Musashi disappear to...
무사시 씨는 대체 어디에 가 버렸을지...
Awesome!
대단해!
Musashi!
무사시!
No! I'll be done for at this rate-dasu! I need something!
안 돼! 이대로는 당하오! 이대로는!
Is there a way to get over-dasu?
어떻게 타개할 방법은 없소?
Secret Sword! Ichi no Tachi!
비검! 제일의 검!
Match set! Jūbee wins!
승부 났습니다! 주베 님의 승리!
That was excellent.
훌륭했다.
I lost...
졌소...
I lost to Jūbee...
나는 주베 씨에게 졌소...
Wh- what is this-dasu?
뭣이오?
It's been a while, Musashi. No, traitor.
오랜만이다, 무사시. 아니, 반역자.
Hanzō!
한조!
Untie this thread-dasu!
이 줄을 푸시오!
You're one guy without common sense.
상황 파악 못하는 놈.
Musashi!
무사시!
Musashi's death penalty is set by this.
이걸로 무사시의 사형은 확정이군.
De- death penalty?
사, 사형?!
Indeed.
그렇다.
You've crept inside the main competition place and acted violently without shame, making you a traitor.
반역자 주제에 또 뻔뻔하게 본대회장에 몰래 들어가고 날뛰었다.
Acted violently?
날뛰었다?
Jūbee asked for an extra match...
그건 주베 씨가 번외 시합을!
Shut up!
닥쳐라!
You have just acknowledged your offense by signing on this!
방금 막 자신의 죄를 인정하는 인감을 한 참이 아닌가!
What?
뭣이오?
I, Musashi, acknowledge the crime I committed myself and agree to be executed no matter what.
나 무사시는 자신이 저지른 죄를 인정하고 사형에 처해져도 어쩔 수 없습니다.
What is this-dasu?! I don't know about this-dasu!
뭣이오, 이건? 이런 건 난 모르오!
Damn...
젠장...
It was all your plan-dasu, Hanzō!
꾸미고 있었소, 한조!
Musashi from Miyamoto village.
미야모토 마을의 무사시.
The time to bury to the afterworld has finally come.
드디어 저 세상으로 매장해 버릴 때가 온 것인가.
How pitiful is Musashi. Will his youthful life will come to an end in Hanzō's hands?
불쌍한 무사시. 한조의 마의 손에 떨어져 그 젊은 삶을 끝내게 되는가.
A young man who just wanted to be a champion in Jipangu Martial Arts Competition is
지팡구 무예 대회에서 우승하는 것을 꿈꾼 젊은이가
about to be executed without being able to make that dream come true.
그 꿈을 이루지 못하고 바야흐로 처형되려 하고 있다.
Will there be anyone who'll save this Musashi, or not?
이 무사시를 구할 자, 과연 있을까, 없을까?
Sometimes the moon jumps over
허공의 주머니에 달이
the pocket of empty sky
뛰어넘어가는 일도 있어
Laugh loudly and
큰 소리로 웃으면
morning will come tomorrow
내일에는 아침이 와
Don't worry too much about losing
잃는 것 따위는 아무것도 아니야
Keep going! Go for it!
계속 해나가! 앞으로 가!
A bare hand is strong
맨손은 강해
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how life is! Look, a chance
인생 그런 거야! 기회가 어라,
follows us wagging its tail!
꼬리를 흔들며 쫒아와!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
미래도 그런 거야! 내일이 어라,
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
양손을 벌리고 웃고 있어!
The martial arts competition is about to end.
무예 대회도 슬슬 끝나 가오.
No way! The final match is Kojirō vs Jūbee.
이게 무슨, 결승전은 코지로와 주베 씨.
Why isn't it me? How frustrating!
왜 내가 아닌 것이오! 분하오!
This is no time to be frustrated-dasu! I'm about to be executed by Hanzō-dasu.
분하고 있을 때가 아니오! 나, 한조에게 사형당하려는 틈이오.
It's no time to become the number one martial artist of Jipangu!
지팡구 제일의 무예가가 될 생각을 할 때가 아니오!
Somebody help me!
누가 도와주시오!
Next story! Karakuri Martial Artists, Go Out at Once-dasu!
다음 이야기! 카라쿠리 검호 총출격!
Watch the stormy twist-dasu!
질풍노도의 대역전을 보시오!
Next Episode
다음 이야기
Karakuri Martial Artists
카라쿠리 검호 총출격
Go Out at Once!
기대하세요!